// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Who invented Java Programming?",
    answer: "James Gosling",
    options: [
         "Guido van Rossum",
         "James Gosling",
         "Dennis Ritchie",
         "Bjarne Stroustrup"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: " Which component is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs?",
    answer: "JVM",
    options: [
        "JRE",
        "JIT",
        "JDK",
        "JVM"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "What is the extension of java code files?",
    answer: ".java",
    options: [
        ".js",
         ".txt",
        ".class",
         ".java"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: " Which of the following is not an OOPS concept in Java?",
    answer: "Compilation",
    options: [
        "Polymorphism",
        "Inheritance",
        "Compilation",
        "Encapsulation"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following is a type of polymorphism in Java Programming?",
    answer: "Compile time polymorphism",
    options: [
        "Multiple polymorphism",
        "Compile time polymorphism",
        "Multilevel polymorphism",
        "Execution time polymorphism"
    ]
  },

    {
    numb: 6,
    question: "What is Truncation in Java?",
    answer: "Floating-point value assigned to an integer type",
    options: [
      " Integer value assigned to floating type",
      "Floating-point value assigned to an integer type",
      "Floating-point value assigned to a Floating type",
      " Integer value assigned to floating type"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: " Which exception is thrown when java is out of memory?",
    answer: "OutOfMemoryError",
    options: [
      " MemoryFullException",
      "MemoryOutOfBoundsException",
      "OutOfMemoryError",
      "MemoryError"
    ]
},

{
    numb: 8,
     question: "Which of these are selection statements in Java?",
    answer: "if()",
    options: [
          " for()          ",
          "if()          ",
          " continue",
          "break"
        ]
},

{
    numb: 9,
    question: " Which of these keywords is used to define interfaces in Java?",
    answer: "interface",
    options: [
              " Interface",
              "interface",
              "Intf",
              "intf"
    ]
},
{
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which of the below is not a Java Profiler?",
    answer: " JVM",
    options: [
      " JVM ",
      " JConsole",
      " Eclipse Profiler",
      " JProfiler"
    ]
},       
        
];